{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following bacteria genus is capable of oxidizing ammonia (NH4)?", "opta": "Nitrospina", "optb": "Nitrobacter", "optc": "Nitrosococcus", "optd": "Nitrosobacter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A group of about 300 chlorophyll molecule acting together to trap photons and transfer energy to the pigment molecule at the reaction center may be called as", "opta": "harvesting unit", "optb": "reaction center", "optc": "photosynthetic unit", "optd": "chloromass", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chief source of nitrogen for green plants is", "opta": "atmospheric nitrogen", "optb": "nitrates", "optc": "ammonium salts", "optd": "low molecular weight- organic nitrogenous compound", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of long chain alcohol is esterified to plant chlorophyll molecules?", "opta": "Dolichol", "optb": "Farnesol", "optc": "Phytol", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During nitrogen fixation the enzyme nitrogenase catalyse the reaction. The reaction is high energy demanding which require approximately", "opta": "12 ATP", "optb": "18 ATP", "optc": "25 ATP", "optd": "7 ATP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following molecule is produced from the fixation of CO2 in C4 plants?", "opta": "Malate", "optb": "Oxaloacetate", "optc": "Pyruvate", "optd": "Alpha-ketoglutarate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plants absorb nitrates from soil and convert them into", "opta": "urea", "optb": "ammonia", "optc": "nitrogen", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the presence of carbon monoxide, nitrogen fixation", "opta": "increases", "optb": "decreases", "optc": "inhibits", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An organism that relies exclusively on pre-synthesized food molecules is", "opta": "autotrophic", "optb": "photosynthetic", "optc": "prokaryotic", "optd": "heterotrophic", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the Calvin cycle of C3 plants, which molecule is the acceptor of CO2?", "opta": "Erythrose-4-phosphate", "optb": "Ribulose-l,5-diphosphate", "optc": "Ribose-5-phosphate", "optd": "Alpha-ketoglutarate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A major plant macronutrient found in nucleic acids and proteins is", "opta": "calcium", "optb": "nitrogen", "optc": "sulphur", "optd": "iron", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the metal ligand in chlorophylls?", "opta": "Copper (Cu)", "optb": "Iron (Fe)", "optc": "Magnesium (Mg)", "optd": "Manganese (Mn)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitrosomonous and Nitrobacter obtain their carbon for growth from", "opta": "organic compounds", "optb": "carbon dioxide", "optc": "elementary carbon", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chlorophyll is associated with", "opta": "thylakoids", "optb": "stroma", "optc": "cristae", "optd": "matrix", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Organisms capable of converting N2 to NO3 are", "opta": "yeasts", "optb": "bacteria", "optc": "roundworms", "optd": "moulds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following aid plants in the acquisition of nitrogen from nitrogen gas of the atmosphere?", "opta": "Bacteria", "optb": "Algae", "optc": "Nematodes", "optd": "Moulds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}